This video will get you started with the
Tessel framework, turning your idea and
thoughts into a spec which will be the
source of truth.
From within my agent, I'll say I want to
create a Hangman CLI game.
There's no need to flood the agent with
too much information as the
bootstrapping process asks me more
questions about what I want to create.
And of course, I can add more to the
spec and add detail at a later point as
part of normal development.
I'm asked about my preferred language,
testing framework, and some questions
about some of the basic requirements as
part of the bootstrapping process.
Now that we've given our guidance on
these decisions, the environment can be
set up. This will include creating TS
config and package JSON files as well as
setting up Vitest.
This creates a project environment that
will allow us to create our application
but test and validate that our generated
code adheres to the requirements in our
spec.
Directories are created for our spec
files, generated code files, and test
files.
Once this is done, we can create the
spec via the Tessel MCP server which
Claude invokes.
While this runs, let's take a look at
what has been created on our file
system.
Our environmental bootstrapping
decisions have been captured in our
agent's MD file.
This includes our language and testing
preferences.
Our directory structure has been
created. There's nothing in our source
or test directories as we haven't
generated anything just yet.
Our various dependency and testing
environments are also set up.
Our specs folder will contain all the
specs for our project and it looks like
Tessel has finished the spec creation
task already.
Our Hangman game spec contains a short
brief of what we're trying to create
with a list of capabilities, some of
which we were asked about during the
bootstrapping process.
We also have an API structure for the
application which looks good.
I might make a quick change to make sure
the game has a visual element to it as
well.
Let's go back to our agent and suggest
the change we want to see in the spec.
In this case, add a visual Hangman
element after each turn.
This is now an iterative process we can
do either with an agent or simply by
manually editing our spec file in our
IDE of choice.
I'd recommend you use the development
environment you're most comfortable
with.
Again, this invokes Tessel's MCP server,
but this time, rather than running the
create tool, it's the edit tool that is
used, as we want to update an existing
spec.
Looks like Tessel has completed the
update, so let's take a look at the
changes that have been made.
Back in the spec file, we can see a new
visual Hangman drawing section, which
does a good job describing the stages of
the Hangman visual with the gallows and
the stages of the Hangman.
I'm happy with this spec now, and we can
proceed to the next stage.
We have created and edited a Tessel spec
via Tessel's MCP server within Cloud
Code.
Our next step is to turn the spec into
an application and generate the code via
the Tessel framework's build
functionality.